Finding Aid for the Jerry W. Southwood Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Jerry W. Southwood Collection
1948-1993
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0553
2.50 linear_feet
Biography/History
Jerry W. Southwood attended Vanderbilt University receiving a Bachelor of Arts degree in 1967. He did the visual research and identification of the images, and donated the photographs to Special Collections in 2002.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains 155 photographs, in 75 file folders, and one video-tape for the documentary “50 Years of Memorial Magic” relative to Men and Women’s Basketball played in Memorial Gymnasium at Vanderbilt University. The images represent formal team photographs, individual players, coaches, and action shots from selective games. The collection is arranged chronologically into three series: Series I contains formal men’s team photographs; Series II contains men’s players, coaches, and action shots; Series III contains women’s players, coaches, and actions shots for the 1992 and 1993 seasons only; and, Series IV contains selective images of Nashville, Tennessee, and Vanderbilt University.
- Series I – Men’s Teams
  - 1948-49 – (2)
  - 1949-50
  - 1951-52 – (2)
  - 1952-53
  - 1953-54
  - 1954-55 – (2)
  - 1955-56
  - 1956-57
  - 1957-58
  - 1958-59 – (2)
  - 1959-60 – (2)
  - 1960-61 – (2)
  - 1961-62 – (2)
  - 1962-63 – (2)
  - 1963-64 – (2)
  - 1964-65 – (2)
  - 1965-66
  - 1966-67
  - 1967-68 – (2)
  - 1968-69 – (2)
  - 1969-70
  - 1970-71
  - 1971-72
  - 1972-73
  - 1973-74 – (2)
  - 1974-75
  - 1975-76
  - 1976-77 – (2)
  - 1977-78 – (2)
  - 1978-79 – (3)
  - 1979-80 – (2)
  - 1980-81
  - 1981-82 – (2)
  - 1982-83 – (2)
  - 1983-84 – (2)
  - 1984-85 – (2)
- Series II – Men’s Players, Coaches, Action Shots
  - Vanderbilt vs. Kentucky – (5), 1959
  - Roy Skinner, Head Coach – (1), 1959
  - Perry Wallace – (1), 1966
  - Duke Squad – (1), 1967
  - Vanderbilt vs. Davidson – (8), 1967
  - Vanderbilt Wins – Final Score: 81-79
  - Bob Bundy and Coach Roy Skinner – (1), 1968
  - Tom Hagan and Kenny Campbell – (1), 1968
  - Vanderbilt vs. LSU – (5), 1969
  - Roy Skinner, Head Coach - (1), 1970
  - Practice Session
  - Vanderbilt vs. Kentucky – (8), 1973
  - Vanderbilt Wins - Final Score: 76-75
  - Vanderbilt Practice Session – (1), 1974
  - Vanderbilt vs. State – (6), 1974
  - Vanderbilt vs. LSU – (11), 1979
  - Vanderbilt vs. LSU- (6), 1980
  - Vanderbilt vs. Tennessee – (5), 1981
  - Vanderbilt vs. Tennessee – (6), 1985
  - Vanderbilt vs. Louisville – (3), 1992
  - Eddie Fogler, Head Coach – (1), 1993
  - Players – (1), 1993
  - Billy McCaffrey, Chris Lawson, Kevin Anglin, Bruce Elder
  - Spectators – (2), 1993
  - ‘Vandy Lance’ – Vanderbilt’s #1 Fan
  - Crowd Scene
  - Vanderbilt vs. Arkansas – (7), 1993
  - Vanderbilt vs. Kentucky – (10), 1993
- Series III – Women’s Players, Coaches, Action Shots
  - Phil Lee, Head Coach – (1), 1991
  - Women’s Basketball Coach, 1981-1991
  - Vanderbilt vs. Bowling Green – (5), 1992
  - 1992 – Jim Foster, Head Coach – (2)
  - Practice Session
  - Practice Session
  - Jim Foster, Head Coach – (3) Game Time, 1992
  - Vanderbilt vs. LSU- (4), 1993
  - Vanderbilt vs. Southern – (2), 1993
  - Individual Players – (2), 1993
  - Rhonda Blades
  - Misty Lamb
- Series IV – Nashville and Vanderbilt University
  - Nashville, Tennessee
    - Tennessee State Capitol, n.d. – (1)
    - Parthenon, n.d. – (1)
    - Cheekwood, n.d. - composite with 2 images
    - Grand Ole Opry, n.d. – (1)
    - Opryland Show, n.d. – (1)
  - Vanderbilt University
    - Campus Scenes, 1985 – (2)
    - Campus Scenes, 1988 – (1)
    - Olin Hall of Engineering, n.d. – (1)
    - Sarratt Student Center, n.d. – (1)